

Ilpo Viertola

Professional to be in deep learning.

I am a forward-thinking deep learning doctoral researcher, interested in multimodal deep learning and generative AI. I have always enjoyed research work, finding it both challenging and immensely rewarding. My work background in fast-paced R&D teams of big companies has given me a great set of tools to thrive in my academic career.

Contact

Address

Teiskontie 12 F 96, 33540 Tampere

Phone

+358405876877

Web

Ilpo.viertola@gmail.com <u>www.github.com/ilpoviertola</u> www.linkedin.com/in/ilpo-viertola/

Expertise

MATLAB

Deep Learning

Communication

Machine Learning

Signal Processing

Optic Laboratory Work

Creativity/Problem solving

Python/R/C++/Java/Ruby

Language Skills

Finnish - Native

English - Full professional proficiency Swedish - Limited working proficiency

Honors & awards

2023 Graduation with Distinction Issued by Industrial Research Fund at Tampere University of Technology

Work Experience

2023- Doctoral Researcher | Tampere University

Multimodal deep learning, content generation, and user control in content synthesis. Synthesised media evaluation and detection.

2023-2023 Software Engineer | Microsoft Oy

Building image quality analysis and testing tool for camera device image quality tuning purposes. Both front- and backend

development.

2021-2023 Trainee | AAC Technologies Oy

As a trainee I have taken apart and gathered knowledge in the:

- Designing and developing an automatic image quality tuning framework
- Implementing and designing objective and subjective image quality metrics

Education

2023- Doctor of Philosophy - Computer Science

Applying deep learning methods in the field of computer vision.

2021-2023 Master of Science

Faculty of computer science. Major in signal processing and machine learning, with a focus on the field of computer vision.

Minor in data science.

MSc thesis: www.urn.fi/URN:NBN:fi:tuni-202304123649
BSc thesis: www.urn.fi/URN:NBN:fi:tuni-202104233419

2021-2022 Master of Science - exchange study period

The exchange study period in Paris Lodron Universität in Salzburg, Austria. I was studying in the faculty of computer science.

Reference

Timo Gerasimow

Senior manager, AAC Technologies Oy

Phone: +358452307932

 $\textbf{Email:} \ \, \textbf{timogerasimow@aactechnologies.com}$